

# **ROMAN KOLISNYK**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm 25 and about 2+ years I work as a web developer and just adore this profession.

I have experience working with difficult projects, I use modern tools for web development, I often use frameworks, libraries, preprocessors, task managers, the console and "push" changes to Github. I know the principles of site building, BEM methodology, the principles of speed optimization, semantic, clean and clear code, I like beautiful, fast and thoughtful interfaces. I'm not afraid of responsibility, I do my work seriously and always try to be better than yesterday.

# **SKILLS**

## Languages of communication:

Ukrainian (native), Russian (fluent), English (Upper-Intermediate level)

### Development languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript (ES5+), PHP

## Libraries / frameworks / preprocessors:

jQuery, SASS, SCSS, Ajax, Bootstrap, Pug (Jade), Jekyll, React (learning now)

#### Instruments:

Gulp, Webpack, Git, console, npm, Bower Methodologies / layouts / other stuff:

BEM, crossbrowser & adaptive layout, CSS & SVG animation, valid & semantic code, pixel-perfect

## **Graphic apps / tools:**

Sketch, Photoshop, Avocode, Zeplin, Figma CMS:

Wordpress, Opencart, BlackLamp, GetSimple, Web-autoresource, Textolite

## Corporate tools:

Bitrix24, Redmine, Trello, Slack

# **EDUCATION**

# NATIONAL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF UKRAINE "KIEV POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE" | 2011 - 2017

Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Automation

- Department of automation of electromechanical systems and electric drive

# **EXPERIENCE**

## FRONT-END DEVELOPER, HEXA LLC

Sep 2018 - now

#### Duties

- · Creating sites from scratch
- Writing additional functionality/plugins
- Landing layout on CMS
- Creating emails & banners
- Debugging
- Manual QA testing

### Results

- Launched a lot of new sites
- Redesigned and rewrited order form/clients&stuff cabinet
- Fixed major bug with banners & created own plugin for its responsivity
- Created several modules for order form

Stack: Javascript, jQuery, PHP, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ajax

## WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, FREELANCE

Jan 2018 - Mar 2019 (14 months)

### Duties

- Creating of Internet shops, landing pages and turnkey sites
- Redesign of sites, optimization and bug fixes
- Writing additional functionality/modules
- Creation of designs and landing layouts on CMS
- Set up hostings & servers
- SEO

# **INTERESTS**

- Technologies and programming
- Electroguitars and rock/metal music
- Bodybuilding & ping-pong
- Films with a taste

#### Results

- Launched 6 new projects
- Redesigned online store Басейн. укр written on Yii2
- Created a new design for the BMWfix store and landed on CMS Web-Autoresource, written in PHP, jQuery and VueJS. Also some modules and extra-functionality were written for the front-end part of the site using PHP, JS and the jQuery library
- Completely rewritten groomroom.net, redesigned, connected plug-ins, admin panel and created and configured forms for recording clients

**Stack:** Javascript, jQuery, PHP, Yii2, HTML, Pug (Jade), CSS, SASS, Ajax

# WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, SP-CARPARTS & PATRUBOK

Jan 2016 - Aug 2018 (1.8 year)

#### Duties

- Redesign of the site, landing layout on CMS
- Writing new functionality
- Connecting modules
- · Content management
- · Code optimization and debugging
- SEO
- Maintenance of the site, etc.

#### Results

- Redesigned sites with responsiveness and cross-browser compatibility
- The module for notification of payment/return of goods was created, and partners program for downloading/uploading pricelists, configured LigPay
- Implemented the ability to create news
- The sites code was optimized and improved Google PageSpeed results
- Connected and configured a lot of online catalogs and created their own ones

**Stack:** Javascript, jQuery, PHP, HTML, CSS, SASS, Ajax